Paria Sabet

+16723551331 | pariasabet13@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/pariasabet | github.com/PariaSabet | codepen.io/PariaSabet13 | jamparia.dev

SUMMARY

Software Developer with over 5 years of experience specializing in modern web technologies and platforms, including React, TypeScript and CSS. Skilled in UI/UX design, animations, and enhancing customer experiences. At Browse AI, a high-growth, VC-backed AI SaaS startup, contributed to scaling ARR from \$30k to nearly \$2 million and attracting over 500,000 users. Excellent communicator and team player with strong problem-solving abilities and a passion for creating intuitive and engaging user interfaces.

SKILLS

React, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS / SCSS / Sass, Next.js, Vanilla JS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, UI/UX Design, ThreeJS, Graphic design, REST APIs & GraphQL, Zustand, Vite, SQL, Angular, jQuery, Adobe creative suite, Figma, Webflow, Framer, Prismic, Wordpress, Git, TFS

EXPERIENCES

Frontend Developer, Browse AI, Vancouver, Canada

March 2022- Present

- Developed a library of UI components using ReactJS, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, and Storybook, customizing and extending components from libraries like React Aria, Headless UI, Ant Design, and Tailwind UI to meet specific project requirements.
- Initiated a refactor of our Robot Studio client app, utilizing Zustand for state management and implementing the Shadow DOM, eliminating duplicate code, and maximizing the reuse of existing components.
- Developed the front end of a custom authorization system similar to Auth0 and migrated the codebase from Create React App to Vite.
- Utilize advanced CSS techniques, including animations, to create dynamic and engaging user interfaces.
- Integrated our dashboard with back-end services using REST APIs and GraphQL.
- Deployed log monitoring dashboards on Datadog, enhancing system reliability and performance tracking.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers and participated in design reviews to translate design concepts into functional layouts, ensuring consistency between design intent and implementation.
- Conducted A/B testing to evaluate design variations and analyze user interactions.
- Collaborated with the customer success team to identify user pain points and enhance satisfaction and engagement.
- Built layouts and components using Webflow and Prismic for content management to align design and marketing specifications.

Frontend Developer, Kharazmi IT Development

April 2019-March 2022

- Developed and maintained a PWA for the bank's warehouse management using Angular.
- Led the implementation of Business Process Management Systems (BPMS) using ProcessMaker, where I utilized pure
 JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap to build forms.
- Modified and implemented new features for the existing user-tracking web app using the Leaflet library.
- Build dynamic animations using advanced CSS and JS for different use cases, elevating user experience and testing crossbrowser compatibility.
- Led the development and integration of our dashboard with external services using REST APIs.
- Created **UI designs**, **prototypes**, **wireframes**, and **mockups**. Evaluated **UI/UX designs** with other team members to ensure optimal technical implementation.
- Implemented CRM and help desk dashboards using React.js and ASP.NET.
- Programmed Windows Form applications with Entity Framework and SQL Server for the company's internal projects.
- Designed database schemas to store user data with SQL Server.

Frontend Developer Intern, Sklipper

July 2014-December 2017

- Designed and developed multiple web pages for various businesses on the Linux operating system with HTML, CSS,
 JavaScript, Node.js, and MongoDB, along with ensuring optimal responsive design.
- Created game elements and animations using Illustrator and Photoshop for an app called Persona
- Conducted data analysis and provided actionable recommendations while actively participating in brainstorming sessions
 and offering valuable input, driving new product development, strategic decision-making, and boosting team creativity and
 innovation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts

Software Engineering, Guilan University, February 2018

LANGUAGES

- English IELTS 8
- Persian Native
- French Beginner